### Contact

leo@superarts.org

www.linkedin.com/in/superarts (LinkedIn)

### Top Skills

**KMM** 

Github Actions

Kotlin

### Languages

English (Full Professional)

Chinese (Native or Bilingual)

Spanish (Elementary)

Japanese (Elementary)

### Certifications

35 Certificates - American Bankers Association 2017

### **Patents**

A method of appending interaction to handhold electronic devices

A disposable digital audio playing device

A method of protecting hearing via volume adjustment based on media player

# Leo Liu

iOS Architect

Greater Indianapolis

# Summary

More than 10 years of iOS development experience since June 2008, and 3 years Android development experience since September, 2010. Senior Software Engineer experience since July 2004. Strong technical skills in architecture, and always focusing on solving the actual business problem using the right technology.

## Experience

Mastech Digital
iOS Solution Architect
March 2019 - Present (4 years 1 month)
Indianapolis, Indiana Area

- Setting up coding standard and design patterns
- Architecture design / coding in Swift / KMM (iOS + Android)
- Managing mobile solution architecture documentation

#### Chase

Assoc Software Engineer (Senior iOS Developer)
June 2018 - March 2019 (10 months)

- Greater New York City Area
- Architecture design, code review, tech analysis, mentorship.
- Implementing new features / bug fixing for Chase retail app and JPM private banking app.
- Helping transitioning MVC design pattern to MVVM

Cross River Bank Lead iOS Developer December 2016 - May 2018 (1 year 6 months) Greater New York City Area

Working on a retail banking app.

- Based on Swift 3 then Swift 4
- Architecture using VIPER + MVVM (ReactiveCocoa / ReactiveSwift)
- Setting up and developing VSTS / Fastlane based CI system

Super Art Software, Tao Soft, Bamtboo Inc. CEO / CTO / Co-founder January 2008 - December 2016 (9 years) Sydney, Australia

Super Art Software, since 2008

Developed various apps for famous clients in China such as Pingan Bank (id358327241), iFeng HD (id370532345), Anatomy Pronunciations (id319654053), etc.

Participated in several iPhone courses as teacher in Beijing, China, including a series of official iDUP (iPhone Developer University Program) training courses held by Beijing Normal University and Apple Inc.

Created an on-the-fly media serving system PHPAV, which joins and serves media files to user dynamically. Mp4 and flv formats were supported. This system was implemented with PHP, and was replaced by CastAV because of performance and flexibility considerations. There was an XML profile mechanism as well.

Created an on-the-fly media serving system CAV, which is a replacement of PHPAV. It allows various media operation, such as joining, adding metadata, trimming, etc. on various media formats (containers mostly), including mp4/mov, flv, mp3, ogg, vob/mpeg2, wmv/asf, etc.

Created multiple toolkits and scripts for the production servers.

\_\_\_\_

Tao Soft, since 2010

- Worked on several iPhone apps during this period of time.
- Example iOS Project: Suar Photo Sharing
- https://itunes.apple.com/au/app/suar-photo-share/id479530843?mt=8
- A social networking app I've been working on before I was employed in Australia. It's my personal project and I wrote a GAE based NoSQL engine to back it up. It's very much like the Parse API and actually I have built some similar thing based on AWS as well, which was used by another app called Readish, and eventually in my recent project I moved to Parse.

----

Bamtboo Inc., CTO since 2013

Mobile app development, back-end development, and back-end maintenance.

- Back-end service written in Swift, powered by Vapor
- Android development with Android Architecture Components by Google
- iOS: bimo.live

#### VML

Senior iOS Developer October 2016 - November 2016 (2 months)

- Working on Sprint Post-paid iOS app
- Using MVP design pattern
- Feature implementation, bug fixing, and code review

### VML

Senior iOS Developer May 2016 - August 2016 (4 months)

Sydney, Australia

- Worked on the iOS app of Macca's Monopoly 2016 Campaign
- Designed and implemented an architecture with an iOS project that handled most business logic, with a Unity layer with full 3D experience
- 2017 AMY Awards Best Smartphone or Tablet Application Retail & Consumer Goods: http://www.campaignbrief.com/2017/07/clemenger-bbdo-melbourne-score-5.html
- YouTube footage: https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=hGo6wR9BksQ
- https://maccasplay.com.au

#### AirService

Senior iOS Developer August 2015 - April 2016 (9 months)

- Adding features to existing AirService iOS and Android products, including geo-fencing, socket based real time communication, push notification, iBeacon, payment gateway, and others.
- Creating automated build environment using technologies like Fastlane, Go server, and customised Ruby scripts for iOS and Android.

Black Citrus Senior iOS Developer April 2015 - August 2015 (5 months) Sydney, Australia

- Working on a new project as lead iOS developer
- Worked on several existing iOS projects as mobile developer, including iComplain, ScoreCube, etc.
- Worked on iOS development for www.airservice.com.

Hatching Lab Senior Mobile Developer May 2014 - April 2015 (1 year) Sydney, Australia

- Involved in the development of Tipi app v1.2
- Developed CompanySecret from architecture design, implementation, to debugging

Mpire Media Senior Mobile Developer March 2011 - February 2014 (3 years) Bentley, Western Australia

Worked on several iOS and Android projects, including Music Charts Player, Flipevent, Android Antivirus & Security, etc.

Fully responsible of creating and maintaining mobile apps based on company's marketing direction. Building apps for different affiliates in multiple regions. Reviewing product specifications based on - technical aspect and making advice. Keeping all the projects on schedule.

Cooperating with marketing department to make quick changes based on live marking result. Monitoring tracking status and reporting regularly.

Cooperating with web development team to design new protocols, implement new features, and analyze and fix issues.

Cooperating with a newly founded Croatian mobile development team to work together on some recent mobile apps, e.g. App Lounge, Cloud Miner, etc.

Taking care of modules outsourced to other independent developers.

Mobiquest Solutions Pte Ltd Senior iOS Developer June 2010 - December 2010 (7 months) Singapore

Worked on several iPhone apps architecture design and implementation.

Lead projects to production based on various requirements of the clients. Although the initial product spec and product schedule should always followed, for some (large cooperation) clients sometimes there are additional requirements due to their own business modal. My duty is also to work on their new requirements and make arrangements to ensure the products' quality, and make them go live as soon as possible.

Finished projects include apps for Citibank Singapore, Citibank Australia, PAssion Card (EZ-Link), and I2R in Singapore.

ATEN International Co., Ltd.
Senior Software Engineer
March 2007 - March 2008 (1 year 1 month)
Shanghai, China

Participated in IGSM, a cross-platform server management system. Worked on a Quick Cursor module, details including protocol paring and handling, and screen drawing.

Participated in iKVM, a cross-platform control panel of ATEN KVM products. Worked on a Virtual USB module, making it a platform independent lib, and work on both Windows and Linux. Some GDI/X11 based GUI programming was involved as well.

Worked on CN6000 firmware customization, which was based on a build-in web server, which was implemented by C on embedded Linux. Most works were done with C / HTML / Java Script.

Participated in project management, version control, and documentation writing of various projects.

Participated in testing and debugging of various projects.

Serial Microelectronics Pte Ltd Project Manager March 2006 - March 2007 (1 year 1 month)

Shenzhen, Guangdong, China

- Created and designed media transcoding application MP4Maker and related CD Media Tools for the MSilicon MP4/PMP product line. It was implemented with Borland C++ Builder.
- Participated in porting Lua Virtual Machine, DirectFB, GNUBoy, MPlayer to MSilicon customized Linux as programmer. Most codes were done with C. Various GNU tools involved, such as make, configure, etc.
- Implemented and led Inovix IMP-2010 MP4 Player to mass production as project manager and programmer. The programming works were based on C and Lua.

### Inventec

Software Engineer; Project Manager July 2004 - March 2006 (1 year 9 months)

Tianjin, China

- Participated in STUN API Module project in the VOIP Team. The primary goal of this project was to implement a cross-platform STUN Library. Works included architecture design, documentation, and programming. Implemented with C (lib) and C++ (sample application).
- Worked as the leader of MP3/PMP Team. Participated in several projects based on various solutions, including but not limited to SigmaTel 35xx, Action, Xware, etc. Main duties included project management, documentation & coding (product spec, architecture design, module programming, etc.), internal training for new colleagues, new solution study and evaluation, production follow-up (including development, internal testing, QA testing, pilot run, mass product, and upgrading). Participated in 3 MP3 Player projects as system designer, project manager, and developer. Participated in 8 MP3/PMP projects as system designer and project manager.
- Created, proposed, and wrote 3 patent applications, which were accepted by SIPO China (www.sipo.gov.cn).

### Education

Tianjin University
Bachelor's Degree, Applied Mathematics · (2000 - 2004)